Sanetoshi - 16 Years Ago - Morning of the attack - I figured out the identity of people. So I activated it at the destination of fate. But then, she showed up...
I realized one morning...
ある朝　気がついたんだ
that I hate this world.
僕はこの世界が嫌いなんだって
This world is made of countless boxes.
世界はいくつもの箱だよ
People bend and stuff their bodies into their own boxes.
人は体を折り曲げて　自分の箱に入るんだ
And stay there for the rest of their lives.
ずっと一生そのまま
And they eventually, inside the box, they forget:
やがて箱の中で忘れちゃうんだ
What they looked like.
自分がどんな形をしていたのか
What they loved; who they loved.
何が好きだったのか
誰を好きだったのか
That's why I'm getting out of my box.
だからさ　僕は箱から出るんだ
I'm one of the chosen.
僕は選ばれし者
That's why I'm going to destroy this world.
だからさ　僕はこれからこの世界を 壊すんだ
ed
桃果よ
I'm Momoka.
眞悧だよ
I'm Sanetoshi.
I'm going to banish you from this world.
あなたをこの世界から追放するわ
How electrifying.
痺れるな
どうやって
How are you going to do that?
The spell to transfer fates is written in here.
ここに運命の乗り換えをする呪文が書いてある
これを唱えれば　これでみんなを救える
If I cast it,
I can save everyone.
そして　あなたを永遠の闇に吹き飛ばすの
And I'll blow you out into oblivion.
In that case, I shall seal you inside a curse.
なら僕は　君を呪いの中に閉じ込めるとしよう
呪文は半分で終わり
The spell will only be half-cast,
君はすべてを救えない
and you won't save everything.
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
少年少女輪になって
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
交わらないイマジナリー
majiwaranai imaginary
The Imaginary and the Real can never mingle
回転木馬宙を舞って
kaiten mokuba chuu wo matte
The merry-go-round twirls into the air
戦いの幕を切って落とす
tatakai no maku wo kitte otosu
As the curtain of war is torn open
秘め事明かすホーリーナイト
himegoto akasu holy night
The Holy Night for divulging secrets
真夜中開く窓
mayonaka hiraku mado temaneku nazo no koe
My window opens at night and a mysterious voice beckons
手招く謎の声
深紅のカーテンを翻して
shinku no curtain wo hirugaeshite hohoemi kakusu
A crimson curtain conceals the smile
微笑み隠す
少年よ我に帰れ
shounen yo ware ni kaere
Boys, come back to me
特急列車乗っちゃって
tokkyuu ressha nocchate
I ended up getting on the midnight express
neverland ni tsuretette
Take me away to Neverland
ネバーランドに連れてって
issai gassai ubatte yo
Steal away everything I have
一切合切奪ってよ
後ろ指さされたって
ushiro yubi sasaretatte
I don't care if you talk behind my back
ichimokusan ni nigechatte iiyo
I'll just run away at full speed
一目散に逃げちゃっていいよ
全部お気に召すまま
zenbu oki ni mesu mama
Do as you please
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
回り始めるディステニー
mawari hajimeru destiny
Destiny begins to turn
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：hunter 翻译:草泥马 校对:冷漠的风  木落 时间轴:wcaster 压制:wcaster
She was deliriously calling out her brother's name when she was carried here last night.
昨日運ばれてきた時
妹さんうわ言でずっとお兄さんの名前を呼んでたよ
何かあったのかい
Did something happen?
Take a little break.
すこし休みなさい　昨日から一睡もしてないんだろう
You haven't slept at all, have you?
How much time does she have left?
後　どのくらいですか　ひまりは
Until tonight or tomorrow morning.
今晩　明日の朝かな
I'm sorry.
すまんね
Where is Dr. Sanetoshi?
眞悧先生はどこなんですか
Sanetoshi?
眞悧　誰の事かね
Who is that?
Oh, I did have an assistant by that name in the past.
アー　そんな名前の助士が昔いたが
昔
In the past?
No, he was in your examination room...
いいえ　僕は先生の診察室で
That reminds me, I had a strange dream few days ago.
そう言えや　先日奇妙な夢を見たよ
I met him for the first time in ages,
その助士と久しぶりに再会して　笑い合って鍋を食べた
and we had a fun time over hot pot.
It sure was a strange dream.
不思議な夢だった
Where is he now?
その人　今は
He passed away 16 years ago.
死んだよ　十六年前に
I think he was calling himself a ghost in the dream.
夢の中で彼は自分を幽霊だって言ってたかな
How unscientific...
非科学的だね
幽霊
A ghost?
Simply put, you're all cursed by a ghost.
つまり　君たちは亡者に呪われているんだ
僕は呪いのメタファーなんだ
I'm an embodiment of the curse.
I want to show it to her face this time.
今度こそ見せつけてやりたいんだ
The sight of world's destruction to the girl in the hat.
帽子の彼女に 世界が壊れるところをね
I want to save Himari, even if the world is destroyed.
世界が壊れても　俺はひまりを助けたい
I'll save her.
助けるよ
How 'bout I show you one of my magic spells?
じゃ　君に一つ　僕の魔法を見せてあげよう
生存戦略
Survival Strategy.
Milady...
お嬢様　お嬢様
Milady?!
She has passed away.
ご臨終です
可哀そうに
Poor girl.
君のふたごの妹は死んでしまったよ
Your twin sister is dead.
Masako... No way...
真砂子　そんな
綺麗な子だ　君とよく似ている
She's a beautiful girl.
The family resemblence is strong.
Now then, prepare to be dazzled.
さて
とくと御覧じろう
Where am I?
ここは
Doctor, she's come to!
先生　お嬢様の意識が
It's a miracle!
奇跡だ
I know, right?
だよね
Where is Mario?
マリオさんは
There's no need worry.
心配いりませんよ　隣の部屋でお休みになっています
He's resting in the next room.
I see. That's good.
そう　よかった
真砂子
Masako...
Do you get it now?
これで分かったろう　僕ならひまりちゃんの命を救えるってことが
I can save Himari.
あ
Yes.
No, Brother.
駄目よ　お兄さん
The world and fate cannot be altered by Houdini's magic.
世界も運命もフーディーニの魔法で変えることだってできないわ
お嬢様　一体なにを
Milady, what are you saying?
Let us go.
さあ　行こう　たくさん壊してくれ
You have much to destroy.
Let's see how many you can kill with the power of love.
試そうよ　君の愛の力で何人壊せるか
No!
駄目よ　冠葉　その列車に乗っては駄目
Kanba, don't get on that train!
Yes. I'll destroy as much as I can.
あ　たくさん壊すさ
Now, you're my best friend.
これで君は僕の親友だ
冠葉
Kanba...
Sho.
晶ちゃん　晶ちゃん
Himari?
ひまり　お前なのか
Is that you?
Do you remember when we went to the beach?
ね　晶ちゃん　覚えてる
皆で潮干狩りに行った日の事
あ　初めて家族揃って行ったんだ
Yeah, we went there for the first time as a family.
I remember it very well.
よく覚えているよ
私は燥いじゃって　迷子になった
I was carried away and got lost.
Yeah.
うん　兄貴と二人で必死に探した
Bro and I desperately searched for you.
どんどん日が暮れて
It kept getting darker and the tide kept creeping in.
潮が満ちて来て
Everyone went home and it was just our family there.
皆帰っていって　僕たち家族だけになって
I was so scared.
怖かった　世界に私一人だけが取り残された気がした
It felt as if I was left behind in the world.
But...
でも
You found me.
見つけてくれたね
Yes.
うん　兄貴と二人で見つけた
The two of us found you.
僕らを見るなり大泣きして
You broke into tears when you saw us!
Oh, right.
そうだ　ひまりがあんなに泣くのを見たのはあれが初めてだった
That was the first time we saw you cry like that.
You're right.
そうだね　私　あの時分かったんだ
That's when I realized...
that I had become a child who would be found.
私は見つけてもらえる子供になれたんだって
だから　嬉しくて泣いたの
So, I broke into tears of happiness.
ひまり
Himari...
どんなに遠く逸れてしまっても
No matter how far we're separated, you two would definitely find me.
晶ちゃんと冠ちゃんがきっと私を見つけてくれる
誰かに見つけてもらえるって　幸せな事だね
It's nice knowing someone will find you.
I was happy and it was fun being with you and Kan.
私　晶ちゃんと冠ちゃんと一緒にいられて　嬉しくて楽しかった
Thank you for everything.
ありがとう
Don't be ridiculous, we'll always be together like we are now.
何言ってるんだよ　これからだってずっと一緒じゃないか
うん　そうだね
Right.
We'll always be together.
私たちはずっと一緒
So, Sho...
だから　晶ちゃん　今度は冠ちゃんを見つけてあげて
Find Kan this time.
見つける
Find Kan?
冠ちゃんはあの時の私と一緒
He's just like I was back then.
Lost.
迷子なんだ
But...
だけど
You're the only one who can stop him.
冠ちゃんを止められるのは晶ちゃんだけだよ
Stop him... Me?
止める　僕が
Please find his heart.
見つけてあげて　冠ちゃんの心を
Kan thinks he's all alone in the world.
冠ちゃん　世界に一人ぼっちだと　泣いてるから
He's crying inside.
冠　葉
Kanba...
ひまりを迎えに来た
I have come to take Himari.
この世界は間違えている　お前も分かってるんだろう
This world is on a wrong track.
You must have noticed.
What are you up to?
何をするつもりだ
We will follow our parent's will.
父さんと母さんの意志を　俺たちが受け継ぐ
Are you out of your mind?
バカ野郎　どうしちゃったんだよ
What's wrong with you?
ひまりはもうじき
Himari is about to...
The day we were born.
俺とお前が生まれた日は　俺たちの運命の至る場所
The destination of our fate.
That's the end of this unfair and cruel world.
それでこの理不尽で不公平な世界は終わる
Himari's life will be saved.
ひまりの命も救われるんだ
Do you intend to to sacrifice the lives of many for that?
大勢の人を犠牲にするつもりか
そんなことでひまりが救えるわけないだろう
How is that going to save Himari's life?
You don't see the truth of this world.
お前にはこの世界の真実が見えてないんだ
The world as it is now will never bear fruit for us.
今の世界は絶対に俺たちに実りの果実を与えたりしない
So, we will change the world.
だから俺たちは世界を変える
I won't allow it.
許さないぞ　そんなことを
I don't need your permission.
許しなど欲しくない
Don't get in my way.
邪魔をするな
Kanba... You...
冠葉　お前
Shoma.
晶馬
ずっと
I've always...
I've always wanted to do this to you.
ずっと　お前をこうしてやりたかったんだ
Yes.
うん　これから晶馬君たちの着替えを持って病院に行くから
I'm about to take a change of clothes to the hospital for Shoma.
They said tonight or tomorrow morning is it for Himari...
ひまりちゃん　今日　明日かもしれないって
I'll be home late, so don't wait for me.
帰りは遅くなるから　ママ先に寝ててね
Ringo - Continuation of the last flashback - To'oh Hospital Lounge - It was a surprise. I finally learned the diary's secret. But I didn't really understand what I would use it for.
返すわ
You can have it back.
やっと分かったの　これは桃果があなたに残した物だった
I've finally realized Momoka left it behind for you.
もう半分を手に入れて　日記を完全な物にするの
Get the other half and complete the diary.
The spell to transfer fate is written somewhere in there.
そのどこかに　運命の乗り換えをする呪文が書かれているわ
呪文
The spell?
There was no such thing...
そんな物　どこにも
きっとどこかに書いてある
I'm sure it's written somewhere in there.
それを使えば　あなたの大切な誰かを救うこともできるわ
You can save someone important to you by casting it.
私　運命を乗り換えようなんて　考えたことない
I've never thought of transferring fate.
そう　でも桃果はあなたにこれを託したの
I see.
But Momoka left this behind for you.
Then, I'm sure the time will come when...
だとしたら　いつかきっと
分かったよ　桃果
I got it, Momoka.
The time is now.
それが今なんだね　わたしがこの日記でひまりちゃんを救うんだ
I will save Himari with this diary!
もしもし　晶馬君
Hello, Shoma?
I've got the other half of the diary, Oginome.
日記のもう半分を手に入れたよ　荻野目さん
Kanba?
冠葉君　今どこにいるの
Where are you?
Where did you get the other...
日記の半分って
Let's join forces.
力を合わせよう　二人でひまりを救おう
Let's save Himari together.
I can't go anywhere right now.
今ここから動けないんだ　奴らに追われてる
They're after me.
"They"?
奴ら　冠葉君　一体どこにいるの
Where are you, Kanba?
冠葉君　どこ
Kanba?
Where are you?
Oginome.
荻野目さん
冠葉君
Kanba?
そっちの日記は持ってきてくれた
Did you bring your half of the diary?
Yes, right here.
あ　うん　ここに
よかった　こっちに来てくれ
Good.
Come this way.
This way?
こっち
そのまま進んで
Keep going.
冠葉君　ひまりちゃん　病院で待ってるよ
Kanba, Himari is waiting for you in the hospital.
She was calling out your name when they brought her in, from what I hear.
倒れた時もずっと冠葉君の名前を呼んでたって
Come on, let's go and see her.
ね　早く行ってあげようよ
Don't worry.
心配いらないよ
We'll go together tomorrow morning.
明日の朝　ひまりと俺は一緒に行くんだ
Go?
行く　どこへ
Where to?
新しい世界だ
To a new world.
それでひまりを救われる
Himari will be saved.
What do you mean?
どういうこと
だって　ひまりちゃんは
Isn't Himari...
What's this, Kanba?
これ何　冠葉君
ありがとう　荻野目さん
Thank you, Oginome.
Hey, how did you know about my diary?
ね　どうして冠葉君が日記の事知ってるの
I haven't told anyone that Yuri gave it back...
ゆりさんに返してもらったってことは　まだ誰にも
友達から聞いたんだ
A friend told me.
友達
A friend?
You know, I was scared.
僕　怖かったんだよね
I had a feeling Momoka would get me again as long as you and that diary existed.
君とその日記が存在してると
また桃果ちゃんにやられちゃうような気がして
あなた　誰
Who are you?
初めまして　僕は幽霊だよ
Nice to meet you.
I'm a ghost.
駄目
No!
How electrifying.
痺れるな
You'd protect that diary even if it destroys your body?
その身を壊しても日記を守りたいんだね
No...
駄目よ　どうしてもこれが必要なの
I absolutely need this...
We're going to use it to transfer Himari's fate!
これで　ひまりちゃんの運命を乗り換えるんだから
Your love is being tested.
君の愛が試されてるんだね
Then, you have to do your best.
じゃあ　頑張らないと
I'll never let it go!
あたし　絶対に手放さないよ
I won't give up on Himari!
ひまりちゃんを諦めない
Come on, the diary will burn to ash if you don't try harder.
ほら　もっと頑張らないと
日記が燃えて消えちゃうよ
I'm sorry.
ごめん
I'm sorry, Himari.
ごめんね　ひまりちゃん
Aww... too bad.
アー　残念だったね
愛の力ではどうにもならないこともあるさ
There are things you can't control with the power of love alone.
でも　君のためにはこれでよかったんだ
But it was in your best interest.
If you cast the spell, the cursed fire would've burned away your entire body.
呪文を使えば　その代償として
呪いの炎にその身のすべてを焼かれちゃうからね
It means you'll be erased from the world's scenery.
世界の風景から失われるってことさ
じゃあ　もう一つの日記も燃やしちゃって
Burn away the other half, too.
I can't touch it, after all.
僕はそれに触れることができないからね
No one knows the spell now.
これで　呪文を知る者は誰もいない
Let us go.
さあ　行こうか
The Destiny Express awaits.
運命の列車が僕たちを待っている
The Destiny... Express?
運命の　列車
ひまり
Himari...
Damn it, Kanba!
冠葉め
おはよう
Good morning.
You're finally awake.
ようやくお目覚めですね　高倉晶馬君
Shoma Takakura.
Hurry.
急いで　運命の列車がもうすぐ出発する
The Destiny Express is about to depart.
You have to get on.
あなたはそれに乗るのよ
Hat... I mean, you're...?
お前　いや　君は
Don't miss the train.
乗り逃がしては駄目
The black bunny is trying to destroy the world.
黒いウサギが世界を壊そうとしている
You two are the only ones who can stop it.
あれを止められるのはあなたたちだけよ
"You two"?
あなたたち
そう　あなたと冠葉君
Yes.
You and Kanba.
Kanba and me?
僕と冠葉
But he...
だって　あいつは
そして　あなたたちはあの列車で見つける
And on that train you two will find...
見つける　何を
Find what?
あなたたちのピングドラムを
Your Penguindrum!
世界が割れて
The Destination of Fate
The world divided and the heroes fell in the abyss of time
時間の溝に生まれ落ちたヒーローたち
I never amounted to anything.
僕は何者にもなれなかった
絵に描いたユートピアを夢見て
Dreaming of the ideal utopia
No, I finally gained power.
いや　僕はついに力を手に入れたんだ
I'm going to take my revenge on the world that never needed me.
僕を必要としなかった世界に復讐するんだ
I finally will become visible.
やっと僕は透明じゃなくなるんだ
自由が重すぎるのさ
Freedom is too much of a burden
幻想が作り上げた
Bury the hero manifested by fantasy
Human beings are such inconvenient creatures.
人間っていうのは不自由な生き物だね
ヒーローを葬り去れ
Why, you ask?
なぜって
だって　自分という箱から一生出られないからね
Because they can never escape the box called "self."
Two is Better
than One
Getting
Along is
Beautiful
It's better than losing to the power and living in a world without video
力に負けて
Those boxes don't protect us.
その箱はね　僕たちを守ってくれるわけじゃない
ビデオさえ許されない世界よりましさ
They take things precious to us away.
僕たちから大切なものを奪っているんだ
Even if someone was next to you,
たとえ隣に誰か居ても
Tear the ideal utopia apart
絵に描いた　ユートピアを破りなよ
you can't tear down the wall and bond.
壁を越えて繋がることもできない
僕らはみんなひとりぼっちなのさ
We're all alone.
Bury the hero from stifled histories
wow 使い古した歴史の
We will never gain anything inside our boxes.
その箱の中で
僕たちが何かを得ることは絶対にないだろう
wow ヒーローを葬り去れ
There are no exits.
出口なんてどこにもないんだ
幻想を作り上げた
Bury the hero manifested by fantasy
No one can save you.
誰も救えやしない
ヒーローを葬り去れ
So, we can only destroy...
だからさ　壊すしかないんだ
ヒーローを葬り去れ
Bury the hero away
the boxes,
箱を　人を
the people,
the world!
世界を
冠葉
Kanba!
You're finally here, Shoma.
来たか　晶馬
Let's settle this once and for all.
決着をつけよう　冠葉
Kanba!
Shoma - Inside the box - 10 years ago - That's where we first met. I think that was when our fate was set in stone.
Where am I?
ここは　どこ
It's no use, I can't remember anything.
駄目だ　何も思い出せない
どうしてこんなところに閉じ込められなきゃいけないんだ
Why do I have to be trapped in here?
How many days have I been trapped here?
ここに入れられて　もう何日が経っただろう
君は誰
Who are you?
お前こそ誰だ
私たちは永遠の約束をするんだ
目を逸らさないよ
すべてがあそこにあるから
生存戦略　輪るピングドラム